<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/atom.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <id>https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/</id>
  <title>sht&amp;apos;s home</title>
  <subtitle>own blog</subtitle>
  <icon>https://bloggersht.com.cn/python</icon>
  <logo>https://bloggersht.com.cn/logo.jpg</logo>
  <updated>2024-12-08T05:54:01.869Z</updated>
  <generator>@vuepress/plugin-feed</generator>
  <link rel="self" href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/atom.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/"/>
  <category term="Web"/>
  <category term="study"/>
  <contributor>
    <name>sht</name>
  </contributor>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">The Static Site Paradox</title>
    <id>https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/blog/2024/TheStaticSiteParadox.html</id>
    <link href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/blog/2024/TheStaticSiteParadox.html"/>
    <updated>2024-11-17T06:19:36.000Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In front of you are two personal websites, each used as a blog and to display basic contact info of the owner:</p>
<ol>
<li>One is a complex CMS written in PHP that requires a web server, multiple workers, a Redis cache, and a SQL database. The site also has a big frontend component that loads as a Single Page Application and then performs navigation by requesting the content in JSON form, which then gets “rehydrated” client-side.</li>
<li>The other is a collection of static HTML files and one or two CSS files. No JavaScript anywhere.
If you didn’t know any better, you would expect almost all normal users to have [2] and professional engineers to have something like [1], but it’s actually the inverse: only few professional software engineers can “afford” to have the second option as their personal website, and almost all normal users are stuck with overcomplicated solutions.</li>
</ol>]]></summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In front of you are two personal websites, each used as a blog and to display basic contact info of the owner:</p>
<ol>
<li>One is a complex CMS written in PHP that requires a web server, multiple workers, a Redis cache, and a SQL database. The site also has a big frontend component that loads as a Single Page Application and then performs navigation by requesting the content in JSON form, which then gets “rehydrated” client-side.</li>
<li>The other is a collection of static HTML files and one or two CSS files. No JavaScript anywhere.
If you didn’t know any better, you would expect almost all normal users to have [2] and professional engineers to have something like [1], but it’s actually the inverse: only few professional software engineers can “afford” to have the second option as their personal website, and almost all normal users are stuck with overcomplicated solutions.</li>
</ol>
<p>Weird as it might be, it’s not a great mystery why that is: it’s easier to spin up a Wordpress blog than it is to figure out by yourself all the intermediate steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Buy a domain</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Find a hosting platform</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Configure DNS</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Find an SSG (or handcraft everything yourself)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Learn how to setup a deployment pipeline</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>And so, while we software engineers enjoy free hosting &amp; custom domain support with GitHub Pages / Cloudflare Pages / etc, normal users are stuck with a bunch of greedy clowns that make them pay for every little thing, all while wasting ungodly amounts of computational power to render what could have been a static website in 99% of cases.</p>
<p>When I published SuperHTML, I discovered that it was the first ever language server for HTML that reported diagnostics to the user. I wrote a blog post about it, it got on the frontpage of Hacker News and nobody corrected me, so you know it’s true.</p>
<p>I originally found it a funny thing, but thinking about it more, it’s a bit sad that this is the case. Linters do exist, and people can get diagnostics in their editor, but that’s usually tooling tied to a specific frontend framework and not vanilla HTML, which leads to people opting to use frameworks even if they don’t really have a real need for all the complexity that those frameworks bring.</p>
<p>And that’s bad in my opinion. Not because of an abstract appreciation for simplicity, but because the web doesn’t belong just to software engineers. The more we make the web complex, the more we push normal users into the enclosures that we like to call social networks.</p>
<p>Don’t you find it infuriating when lawyers and accountants fail to clarify how their respective domains work, making them unavoidable intermediaries of systems that in theory you should be able to navigate by yourself?</p>
<p>Whenever we fail to make simple things easy in software engineering, and webdev especially, we are failing society in the exact same way.</p>
<p>This is not something that startups or big tech can solve for us, their economic incentives are just too misaligned, so I invite you all to help make the web more accessible, partially as a matter of taking pride in our craft, and partially because the web used to be more interesting when more of it was made by people different from us.</p>
]]></content>
    <author>
      <name>sht</name>
    </author>
    <category term="Web"/>
    <contributor>
      <name>sht</name>
    </contributor>
    <published>2024-11-03T13:54:05.000Z</published>
    <rights>Copyright by sht</rights>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">one divided by zero</title>
    <id>https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/study/maths/amazing_maths/one%20divided%20by%20zero.html</id>
    <link href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/study/maths/amazing_maths/one%20divided%20by%20zero.html"/>
    <updated>2024-07-28T12:44:55.000Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>1/0=？</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>In elementary school, teachers emphasize that 0 cannot be a divisor because it is impossible to imagine what would happen if 6 apples were divided among 0 people.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Getting a little older into middle and high school years, we use use the inverse method, which allows us to prove that dividing any number by 0 will not give us 1 because it would result in all numbers being equal to 1, which is contrary to reality.</p>
<p>Proof:
Suppose 10 ÷ 0 = b
Then b x 0 = 10
bx(0+0)=10
10+10=10
So 2 = 1
By analogy, we can also prove that 3 = 1 and 4 = 1 ......</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>By the time we get to college, we can discuss the mathematical concept of limits, where the fraction 1/0 results in a convergence to positive infinity as the numerator 1 and the denominator gradually converge to zero. However, if the denominator becomes a negative infinity, the result will converge to negative infinity. Since there is a huge gap between positive and negative infinity, 1/0 cannot equal both positive and negative infinity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In advanced mathematics, dividing by zero may no longer be a meaningless operation, but an interesting rule related to the expansion of the concept of infinity. As we get deeper into math, especially after learning about negative and complex numbers, we may come to understand the true meaning of dividing 1 by 0. Imaginary numbers are formed by introducing an imaginary number axis outside the real number axis to form the complex plane.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>At this point we introduce the concept of the Riemann sphere, which is formed by curling points on a plane onto a sphere. The points on the sphere correspond to the points on the plane, and the points on the sphere are concentrated near the north pole of the sphere the farther they are from the origin. As the angle of the light becomes smaller, the points on the plane that correspond to the points further away from the origin will also be concentrated near the north pole of the sphere. The north pole of the Riemann sphere corresponds to the point on the plane at infinity, i.e. “1 ÷ 0”.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>So under the rules of the Riemann sphere, the result of dividing by zero is not necessarily positive or negative infinity, but may be a new concept: infinity. This infinity is neither negative nor positive, and at the same time neither real nor imaginary. It has an infinite length and an arbitrary direction, but is no longer a concept of nothingness.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>1/0=？</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>In elementary school, teachers emphasize that 0 cannot be a divisor because it is impossible to imagine what would happen if 6 apples were divided among 0 people.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Getting a little older into middle and high school years, we use use the inverse method, which allows us to prove that dividing any number by 0 will not give us 1 because it would result in all numbers being equal to 1, which is contrary to reality.</p>
<p>Proof:
Suppose 10 ÷ 0 = b
Then b x 0 = 10
bx(0+0)=10
10+10=10
So 2 = 1
By analogy, we can also prove that 3 = 1 and 4 = 1 ......</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>By the time we get to college, we can discuss the mathematical concept of limits, where the fraction 1/0 results in a convergence to positive infinity as the numerator 1 and the denominator gradually converge to zero. However, if the denominator becomes a negative infinity, the result will converge to negative infinity. Since there is a huge gap between positive and negative infinity, 1/0 cannot equal both positive and negative infinity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In advanced mathematics, dividing by zero may no longer be a meaningless operation, but an interesting rule related to the expansion of the concept of infinity. As we get deeper into math, especially after learning about negative and complex numbers, we may come to understand the true meaning of dividing 1 by 0. Imaginary numbers are formed by introducing an imaginary number axis outside the real number axis to form the complex plane.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>At this point we introduce the concept of the Riemann sphere, which is formed by curling points on a plane onto a sphere. The points on the sphere correspond to the points on the plane, and the points on the sphere are concentrated near the north pole of the sphere the farther they are from the origin. As the angle of the light becomes smaller, the points on the plane that correspond to the points further away from the origin will also be concentrated near the north pole of the sphere. The north pole of the Riemann sphere corresponds to the point on the plane at infinity, i.e. “1 ÷ 0”.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>So under the rules of the Riemann sphere, the result of dividing by zero is not necessarily positive or negative infinity, but may be a new concept: infinity. This infinity is neither negative nor positive, and at the same time neither real nor imaginary. It has an infinite length and an arbitrary direction, but is no longer a concept of nothingness.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="color:orange">Finally, the next time someone asks you what 1 ÷ 0 is, you can silently give them a Riemann ball and let them comprehend the mystery for themselves.</span></strong></p>
<p>Q.E.D.</p>
]]></content>
    <author>
      <name>sht</name>
    </author>
    <category term="study"/>
    <contributor>
      <name>sht</name>
    </contributor>
    <published>2024-07-25T23:14:00.000Z</published>
    <rights>Copyright by sht</rights>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title type="text">✨shtのhome✨</title>
    <id>https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/intro.html</id>
    <link href="https://bloggersht.com.cn/en/intro.html"/>
    <updated>2024-07-20T08:24:28.000Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<h1>Self-introduction</h1>
<p>I, from Suzhou, am a coder who loves the second world.</p>
<h2>New Blog, New Beginning</h2>
<p>I'm just a regular junior high school animal.</p>
<h2>So, let me introduce you to this blog(trash)</h2>
<p>Hardware configuration：</p>
<p>Hosted in<a href="https://github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Github-pages</a></p>]]></summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<h1>Self-introduction</h1>
<p>I, from Suzhou, am a coder who loves the second world.</p>
<h2>New Blog, New Beginning</h2>
<p>I'm just a regular junior high school animal.</p>
<h2>So, let me introduce you to this blog(trash)</h2>
<p>Hardware configuration：</p>
<p>Hosted in<a href="https://github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Github-pages</a></p>
]]></content>
    <published>2024-06-17T02:57:24.000Z</published>
  </entry>
</feed>